<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles • Hrvoje Šimić</title>
    <description>A collection of long form articles by Hrvoje Šimić</description>		
    <link>http://shime.sh</link>
    <atom:link href="http://shime.sh/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    
    <item>
      <title>My experience with switching too many apps for personal knowledge management</title>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Personal knowledge management (PKM) is the best thing I discovered in 2019. I&amp;#39;ve since tried a couple of different approaches and too many (six) apps. In this article, I would like to share everything I&amp;#39;ve learned about it over that period.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <link>http://shime.sh/leaving-roam-led-me-back-to-roam</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shime.sh/leaving-roam-led-me-back-to-roam</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When magic works against you</title>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first encountered this concern in the Rails app that I was working on, I was initially impressed. It felt like magic. Like a cool trick to avoid unnecessary complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <link>http://shime.sh/when-magic-works-against-you</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shime.sh/when-magic-works-against-you</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The importance of detachment</title>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All my previous side projects flopped because of this. I looked at them from the perspective of a creator. I was stuck in that role. I didn’t have the experience of all the other people that were supposed to use the end product.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <link>http://shime.sh/the-importance-of-detachment</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shime.sh/the-importance-of-detachment</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The overreaction paradox</title>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My bike got stolen a while back. It happened because I got lazy carrying my bike up the stairs and left it in the much less secure basement. I thought that taking it up the stairs is not worth it. Nothing will happen. No one will steal a bike from my building since it hasn&amp;#39;t happened to any of my neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://shime.sh/the-overreaction-paradox</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shime.sh/the-overreaction-paradox</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write for yourself</title>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a tension that you’ll discover if you start publishing articles. A tension between writing what the world wants from you and what you want to write about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://shime.sh/write-for-yourself</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shime.sh/write-for-yourself</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beware of programming puzzles</title>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most common piece of advice you&amp;#39;ll receive if you want to learn programming is that you should do programming to learn it. While this is well-meaning advice, since doing programming is better than reading about it, it&amp;#39;s incomplete.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://shime.sh/beware-of-programming-puzzles</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shime.sh/beware-of-programming-puzzles</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowing the port one is sailing to</title>
      
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If one does not know to which port one is sailing, no wind is favorable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
      
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://shime.sh/knowing-the-port-one-is-sailing-to</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shime.sh/knowing-the-port-one-is-sailing-to</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing-guided reading</title>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are so many great books to read, but so little time to do it. How to pick a book from a list of hundreds or even thousands of recommended books to read?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://shime.sh/writing-guided-reading</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shime.sh/writing-guided-reading</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I've decided to switch to Hey</title>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Hey came out, I wasn&amp;#39;t sure that I&amp;#39;m going to use it. But, I was interested in trying it out. I thought it was an overpriced email client and that there is too much hype around it. The App store drama didn&amp;#39;t help. Yet, I was interested in it since I would like to stop using Gmail as my primary email address.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://shime.sh/why-i've-decided-to-switch-to-hey</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shime.sh/why-i've-decided-to-switch-to-hey</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The law of ever-increasing entropy</title>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;All happy families are alike; each unhappy family is unhappy in its own way.&amp;quot; These are the famous words of Leo Tolstoy. But why is that the case? It all boils down to the law of ever-increasing entropy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <link>http://shime.sh/the-law-of-ever-increasing-entropy</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shime.sh/the-law-of-ever-increasing-entropy</guid>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
